In the previous module, we
introduced you to several trades
designed to be of use in
either up or down markets.
In this module, we'll explore
a couple of strategies
that may be used
by option traders to take
advantage of a low
in the markets.
By low, I'm referring to a period
of relatively small
movements in the price
of an underlying asset where
volatility is
expected to diminish.
Once again, we'll walk
you through examples of
how each strategy works
and then show you
a practical application
of how such trades may be
created using IBKR's
Trader Workstation.
While we're talking
specifically about
strategies designed
for neutral markets,
don't forget that the
opposite side of each
trade infers higher volatility,
which would appeal to
option traders looking for
larger price movements or
upward shifts in
volatility. Let's begin.